Guide to the James Roy Welch Papers, 1895-1935
Department of Special Collections
James Roy Welch Papers,
1895-1935
Special Collections M0257
Welch, James Roy, 1860-
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1975
Biography
City attorney, San Jose, California (1895) and Superior Court Judge, Santa Clara County, California (1904).
Scope and Content
Legal papers relating to Judge Welch's term as city attorney of San Jose and as Superior Court Judge, Santa Clara County. Also includes a small amount of personal papers and photographs.
Container List
- Judge James Roy Welch Papers re:
  - 1) Reorganization of California Cured Fruit Association
  - 2) Business and struggle with California Prune and Apricot Growers Association ("Sunsweet") 1921
  - 3) City Attorney of San Jose
  - 4) 1920s cases, petitions, bills re: Judges' Conference, Salary, Retirement with State Legislators (public), Friend Richardson (executive).
  - 5) Denial of citizenship to aliens who did not accept draft in 1917
  - 6) Personal and Business Affairs re: automobiles, repairs(where only 32 cars in Santa Clara County.-Welch had Winton Phaeton (sp?)) 1902
- Commissions/ documents: recovered money for depositors on complex Union Savings Bank litigation; (bank looted by officers).
- Calling Cards
- Some photos: Boulder Dam + Death Valley (1935)